Gary Hart was going to be President. Instead he
changed American politics forever.
The Front Runner is a drama, history film directed by Jason Reitman.
Gary Hart, former Senator of Colorado, becomes the front-runner
for the Democratic presidential nomination in 1987.
Hart's intelligence, charisma and idealism makes him popular with young
voters, leaving him with a seemingly clear path to the White House.
All that comes crashing down when allegations of an extramarital affair surface in the media, forcing the
candidate to address a scandal that threatens to derail his campaign and personal life.
Gary Hart, played by Hugh Jackman.
Lee Hart, played by Vera Farmiga.
Bill Dixon, played by J.K. Simmons.
Billy Shore, played by Mark O'Brien.
Irene Kelly, played by Molly Ephraim.
Kevin Sweeney, played by Chris Coy.
The Front Runner is a 2018 American political drama film directed by Jason Reitman, based on the 2014 book All the Truth Is
Out: The Week Politics Went Tabloid by Matt Bai, who co-wrote the screenplay with Reitman and Jay Carson.
The film stars Hugh Jackman, Vera Farmiga, J.
Simmons, and Alfred Molina.
It chronicles the rise of American Senator Gary Hart, the front-runner candidate to be the 1988 Democratic presidential
nominee, and his subsequent fall from grace when media reports suggested he was having an extramarital affair.
The film premiered at the Telluride Film Festival on August 31, 2018, and was theatrically
released in the United States on November 6, 2018, by Columbia Pictures.
It received mixed reviews; while Jackman was praised for his performance, critics said the rest of the cast felt wasted and the film did not "dive deep enough
into its central issues to make a compelling argument." The film was a box-office bomb, earning just $3.2 million against its $25 million budget.
The film explores themes of politics, senator, colorado, politician, biography.
The tone is emotional.